[{"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "RB", "VBN", "TO", "VB", "RB", "."], "qSentId": 26, "question": "What goes through your mind?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBZ", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 27, "answer": "You've just got to get away.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "EX", "VBZ", "DT", "JJ", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 50, "question": "And what is the answer?", "question_pos_tagged": ["CC", "WP", "VBZ", "DT", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 51, "answer": "Well, there's no single answer.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBZ", ":", "PRP", "VBZ", "JJ", ",", "CC", "PRP", "VBZ", "RB", "VBG", "IN", "EX", "VBP", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 77, "question": "So I think perspective probably has to be brought into this, right?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "PRP", "VBP", "JJ", "RB", "VBZ", "TO", "VB", "VBN", "IN", "DT", ",", "RB", "."], "aSentId": 78, "answer": "It's -- it's perspective, but it's also understanding that there are seasons.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["UH", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "DT", "NN", "PRP", "VBD", "IN", "RB", "."], "qSentId": 103, "question": "Do you like what you see for, maybe, the second term Obama already?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "IN", "WP", "PRP", "VBP", "IN", ",", "RB", ",", "DT", "JJ", "NN", "NNP", "RB", "."], "aSentId": 104, "answer": "Oh, I love the man I voted for originally.", "question_ne_tagged": {"PERSON": ["Obama"]}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "PRP", ":", "PRP", "VBZ", "."], "qSentId": 158, "question": "America needs to find other business models, doesn't it?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "VBZ", "TO", "VB", "JJ", "NN", "NNS", ",", "VBZ", "RB", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 159, "answer": "Well, it -- it is.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "VBN", "PRP", "RB", "IN", "NNS", "IN", "VBP", "VBN", "PRP$", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 231, "question": "Does it apply to any form of trauma or are there grades of trauma?", "question_pos_tagged": ["VBZ", "PRP", "RB", "TO", "DT", "NN", "IN", "NN", "CC", "VBP", "RB", "VBZ", "IN", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 232, "answer": "I've seen it happen with people that have lost their children.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "RB", "VBD", ":", "PRP", "RB", "VBD", "DT", "NN", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 247, "question": "What is your emergency?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBZ", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 248, "answer": "We just had -- we just had a shooting at our school.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {"ORGANIZATION": ["Chardon High School"]}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "NNP", "NNP", "."], "qSentId": 254, "question": "Ma'am, what school?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NN", ",", "WP", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 255, "answer": "Chardon High School.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", ",", "JJ", "."], "qSentId": 256, "question": "Chardon High School?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "NNP", "NNP", "."], "aSentId": 257, "answer": "Yes, ma'am.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "RB", "VB", "."], "qSentId": 259, "question": "Where's the shooter with the gun?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "VBZ", "DT", "NN", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 260, "answer": "I don't know.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["WP", "PRP", ":", "WP", "PRP", "RB", ":", "WP", "VBD", "VBG", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "VBD", "PRP", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "IN", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "NN", "CC", "RB", "NN", "RB", "VBZ", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 274, "question": "The moment you were shot, what goes through your mind?", "question_pos_tagged": ["DT", "NN", "PRP", "VBD", "VBN", ",", "WP", "VBZ", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 275, "answer": "What I -- what I really -- what was going through my mind was I had to get out of the high school and really nothing else flows through your mind.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBD", "DT", "NN", "IN", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 280, "question": "How did you deal with it?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "VBD", "PRP", "VBP", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 281, "answer": "I had a lot of support.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", ",", "PRP", "VBD", ",", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 284, "question": "Did -- did you despair?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ":", "VBD", "PRP", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 285, "answer": "I mean, I did, yes.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "PRP", "VBD", "DT", "NN", "IN", "NN", "IN", "JJ", "NNS", "VBG", "PRP", "CC", "VBG", "PRP", "IN", "VBP", "IN", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 291, "question": "Or what was it that they did that helped you?", "question_pos_tagged": ["CC", "WP", "VBD", "PRP", "IN", "PRP", "VBD", "IN", "VBN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 292, "answer": "Well, I had a lot of support from other people texting me and calling me that are in wheelchairs.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "RB", "VBZ", "RB", "VB", "RB", "."], "qSentId": 313, "question": "What was that like for you as his mother?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBD", "IN", "IN", "IN", "PRP", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 314, "answer": "It really doesn't happen really.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBD", "IN", "PRP", "VBD", "RB", "JJ", "WRB", "PRP", "VBD", "RP", "IN", "NN", ",", "CC", ":", "IN", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "RB", "VBG", "CC", "VBG", "."], "qSentId": 326, "question": "What is the prognosis they made?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBZ", "DT", "NN", "PRP", "VBD", "."], "aSentId": 327, "answer": "They said that they were cautiously optimistic when they came out of surgery, but -- so, we're still hoping and praying.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "IN", "NN", "WP", "VBZ", "VBN", "IN", "PRP", "CC", "VBZ", "DT", "NN", "IN", "POS", "JJ", "."], "qSentId": 335, "question": "-- is that a very particular support group that knows exactly what you've been through?", "question_pos_tagged": [":", "VBZ", "IN", "DT", "RB", "JJ", "NN", "NN", "WDT", "VBZ", "RB", "WP", "PRP", "VBP", "VBN", "IN", "."], "aSentId": 336, "answer": "Well, if somebody who has been through it but has an outlook that's positive.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "MD", "VB", "IN", "."], "qSentId": 354, "question": "What do you think of that?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "IN", "DT", "."], "aSentId": 355, "answer": "I would love that.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "."], "qSentId": 358, "question": "Shake on it?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 359, "answer": "Yes.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["."], "qSentId": 373, "question": "Does that bring all back?", "question_pos_tagged": ["VBZ", "IN", "VBG", "DT", "RB", "."], "aSentId": 374, "answer": ".", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "RB", ",", "PRP", "VBD", "TO", ":", "PRP", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "DT", "RB", "NN", "IN", "DT", "PRP", "VBD", "VBG", "IN", "."], "qSentId": 394, "question": "But aside from that, have you set yourself things that you really want to achieve?", "question_pos_tagged": ["CC", "VBP", "IN", "DT", ",", "VBP", "PRP", "VBN", "PRP", "NNS", "WDT", "PRP", "RB", "VBP", "TO", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 395, "answer": "Well, obviously, I had to -- I had to switch around my career a little bit that that I was aiming for.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "RB", "DT", "JJ", "IN", "DT", "NN", "CC", "PRP", "VBP", "RB", "VB", "IN", "MD", "VB", "RB", "RB", "RB", "."], "qSentId": 397, "question": "What would you want to be?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "MD", "PRP", "VB", "TO", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 398, "answer": "I wanted to be just an electrician in the union and I don't believe that can happen practically right now.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {"DATE": ["2011"]}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBD", "VBG", "DT", "NN", "IN", "NN", "NNS", ",", "PRP", "VBP", ",", "NN", ",", "NN", ",", "WDT", "PRP", "VBD", "IN", "CD", "."], "qSentId": 424, "question": "Before you met Tony, what was -- what was your life like?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "PRP", "VBD", "NNP", ",", "WP", "VBD", ":", "WP", "VBD", "PRP$", "NN", "IN", "."], "aSentId": 425, "answer": "I was doing a lot of current therapies, you know, psychiatry, psychology, which I started in 2011.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", ",", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 429, "question": "Did it help, any of that?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "VB", ",", "DT", "IN", "DT", "."], "aSentId": 430, "answer": "Yes, yes.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["RB", ",", "IN", "."], "qSentId": 433, "question": "So, you had -- why don't you tell him what your symptoms were at the time?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", ",", "PRP", "VBD", ":", "WRB", "VBP", "RB", "PRP", "VBP", "PRP", "WP", "PRP$", "NNS", "VBD", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 434, "answer": "Basically, insomnia.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", "NN", "NN", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "IN", "DT", "NN", "VBD", ":", "PRP", "VBD", "IN", "PRP$", "JJ", "NN", ",", "RB", "VBG", ":", "PRP", "VBD", "RB", "JJ", "NNS", "RB", ",", "MD", "RB", "VB", "RP", "WRB", "PRP", "VBD", "DT", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 439, "question": "What was the rock bottom moment for you?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBD", "DT", "NN", "NN", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 440, "answer": "The rock bottom moment for me in a sense was -- it was after my second divorce, just being --I pushed so many people away, couldn't figure out why I felt this way.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "PRP", "VBZ", "JJ", ",", "CC", "PRP", "VBP", "VBN", "DT", "IN", "NNS", "IN", "VBN", "NNS", "CC", "JJ", "NNS", ":", "NN", "DT", "NN", "VBG", "PRP", "VBP", "NN", ",", "PRP$", "VBZ", "NN", "NN", ",", "CC", "EX", "VBZ", "DT", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "IN", "VBD", "IN", "VBN", "."], "qSentId": 446, "question": "What do you say in this situation?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 447, "answer": "Well, it's interesting, and we've done this with hundreds of wounded warriors and different soldiers -- inside every human being we have trauma, his is extreme trauma, and there's a personality in him that was beyond wounded.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "RB", ",", "PRP", "VBZ", "TO", "VB", "RP", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 464, "question": "What advice would you give him?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "NN", "MD", "PRP", "VB", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 465, "answer": "Well, basically, he has to take back his life.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "RB", "."], "qSentId": 517, "question": "He built a small business to start with and one of those young women that worked for him was addicted to meth, is that right?", "question_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBD", "DT", "JJ", "NN", "TO", "VB", "IN", "CC", "CD", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "NNS", "WDT", "VBD", "IN", "PRP", "VBD", "VBN", "TO", "NN", ",", "VBZ", "IN", "JJ", "."], "aSentId": 518, "answer": "Methamphetamine, right.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "."], "qSentId": 519, "question": "Why don't you share with him the story of how you end up in your new business?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "VBP", "RB", "PRP", "VB", "IN", "PRP", "DT", "NN", "IN", "WRB", "PRP", "VBP", "RP", "IN", "PRP$", "JJ", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 520, "answer": "Yes.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "VBD", "VBG", "JJ", "."], "qSentId": 539, "question": "Why wouldn't you listen to Tony Robbins?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "MD", "RB", "PRP", "VBP", "TO", "NNP", "NNP", "."], "aSentId": 540, "answer": "Things were going great.", "question_ne_tagged": {"PERSON": ["Tony Robbins"]}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "."], "qSentId": 548, "question": "What was that like for you?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBD", "IN", "IN", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 549, "answer": "Yes.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "NN", "IN", "NN", "VBZ", "JJ", "IN", "NN", ",", "CC", "PRP", "DT", "VBP", "PRP", "."], "qSentId": 560, "question": "Or do you have a little bit of (INAUDIBLE), which is that ferocity of spirit?", "question_pos_tagged": ["CC", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "DT", "RB", "NN", "IN", "NNP", "NNP", "NNP", ",", "WDT", "VBZ", "IN", "NN", "IN", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 561, "answer": "I think ferocity of spirit is critical for everybody, but we all have it.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "."], "qSentId": 563, "question": "Do we all have it?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "DT", "VBP", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 564, "answer": "You know, we do.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["JJS", "IN", "PRP", ":", "PRP", "VBP", "WP", "POS", "RB", "JJ", "IN", "JJS", "JJ", "NNS", "VBZ", "IN", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "RBR", "IN", "NNS", "PRP", "VBP", "IN", "PRP", "MD", "RB", "VB", "IN", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 600, "question": "Is that a good focus to look at children, to look at other things and say, \"You know, what stopped feeling sorry for myself; it's for him, for her, it's for that\"?", "question_pos_tagged": ["VBZ", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "NN", "TO", "VB", "IN", "NNS", ",", "TO", "VB", "IN", "JJ", "NNS", "CC", "VB", ",", "``", "PRP", "VBP", ",", "WP", "VBD", "VBG", "NN", "IN", "PRP", ":", "PRP", "VBZ", "IN", "PRP", ",", "IN", "PRP$", ",", "PRP", "VBZ", "IN", "DT", "''", "."], "aSentId": 601, "answer": "Most of it -- I think what's really beautiful about most human beings is that we'll do more for others we love than we'll ever do for ourselves.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "PRP", ",", "NNP", "VBZ", "RB", "RB", "."], "qSentId": 611, "question": "Mike, What do you say to these people suffering in America right now?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "WP", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "TO", "DT", "NNS", "VBG", "IN", "NNP", "NN", "RB", "."], "aSentId": 612, "answer": "I got to tell you, Tony is absolutely right.", "question_ne_tagged": {"PERSON": ["Mike"], "LOCATION": ["America"]}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", "VBZ", "JJ", "."], "qSentId": 628, "question": "But actually all those emotions are just barriers to getting back on your feet, aren't they?", "question_pos_tagged": ["CC", "RB", "DT", "DT", "NNS", "VBP", "RB", "NNS", "TO", "VBG", "RB", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", ",", "VBP", "RB", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 629, "answer": "That's correct.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130125pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", ":", "RB", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "IN", "NN", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "RB", "IN", "TO", "VB", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 694, "question": "If I ask you if you can have anyone thing: you can have good health, you can have money, you can have the fame that allows you to inspire people, what would you choose as the one thing?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "PRP", "VBP", "PRP", "IN", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "NN", "NN", ":", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "JJ", "NN", ",", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "NN", ",", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "DT", "NN", "IN", "VBZ", "PRP", "TO", "VB", "NNS", ",", "WP", "MD", "PRP", "VB", "IN", "DT", "CD", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 695, "answer": "I -- certainly, I think without health, you're not around to do anything.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}]